All right, everybody welcome back. To
your favorite podcast. It's the All-in
podcast. It's the summer. It's August
6th. Having a hard time getting a quorum
here on the podcast, but David Friedberg
is here. David Friedberg is back. Our
Sultan of Science. How you doing,
brother?
>> Great to be with you.
>> It's great to be with you. And
everybody loves
when Brad Gerstner is here. He's your
Bruce Wayne if markets are your game. He
brings that non-mistake to your payday.
>> Yeah, I see
>> passes at discount and he gets you one
of those [laughter] fancy Trump
accounts. All right. Welcome back to the
program, Brad.
>> I love it. I love it. You bring the
rhymes back.
>> I bring a little intro back. We've been
trying Chamath is on the road right now.
Chamath is on the road, but we will get
a field report from Chamath and I I
called Daniel somehow Sachs is going to
be here, but you know how he is. He's
always late because you know, he can get
a phone call from very important people,
but he will break in
at some point. Oh, wait I see in the
text
There he is.
>> HEY [laughter] GUYS.
>> YOU MADE IT.
>> HOW DO YOU like my beautiful summer
gilet? [laughter]
>> Uh, it's incredible. It fits perfectly.
You look warm.
>> I don't know how Chamath does this.
>> [laughter]
[music]
>> Well, here's the report everybody. As
everybody knows, Chamath is on the road.
He Oh, here he is. He This is a photo.
Sachs he went
he went to check his data center
progress. I think that's in Colorado or
Nevada where he was building a data
center.
>> that's on Dune.
>> Oh, it's on Dune. Yes, Dune 4. Ah, yes.
Here he is admiring himself.
Oh, look. Here's Nat.
>> [laughter]
>> You know when a meme has reached its
peak when your wife starts dunking on
you. There it is. And here we are. This
was at the Christmas party, I think. Oh,
Brad, you were on CNBC with Andrew Ross
Sorkin. There you go.
>> I wasn't sure if it was my Twitter feed
that was just selecting into it, but it
clearly hit everyone, right?
>> This is a viral thing. This has hit
everything. All right, listen,
>> [laughter]
>> we got a lot to get to. Enough with the
shenanigans and the small talk. Google
had two major shakeups to its AI staff
on Wednesday. Demis Hassabis
has moved to chair of DeepMind and
at Google. Reports describe this as
Demis stepping down or being kicked
upstairs. Uh we'll get into that. But
Google framed it as a promotion and says
he was stepping up. Here's Axios's quote
explaining the shakeup. Quote, Google's
Gemini 3.5 Pro is months behind, with
some company sources telling Axios that
it's in part due to low morale.
Interesting. Several top researchers,
including Gemini's co-lead, have left
the firm for competing AI labs. Jeff
Dean plus three other AI superstars are
leaving Google to start a company called
Discovery Loop. Dean is a legend,
Freeberg, and I think you worked with
him at Google, one of the world's great
AI engineers. He was employee number 30,
joined in 1999, and has worked there,
from what I understand, continuously for
27 years. Discovery Loop's going to be
focused on deep scientific breakthroughs
in AI. Google shares down 4% on the news
of Dean leaving. So, 200 billion in lost
market cap if you want to correlate
those two things. Freeberg, this is your
alma mater. What are your thoughts here?
Is this creative destruction? Maybe
these people weren't delivering and they
wanted fresh blood, or is this just the
siren call of doing a startup in an age
of unlimited capital for AI and
unlimited opportunity just being too
much for the OGs at Google to not take
advantage of?
>> Maybe it's the third bucket, which is if
you're the board and the management,
you're having a debate about how to best
deploy capital. Google has made a
commitment to deploy $200 billion
dollars in capex this year
in AI infrastructure data center build
out. Because of the capex and
accelerated depreciation,
making an investment in AI compute in
the US right now is hugely tax
advantaged. And because of the extreme
demand for compute,
it's a pretty obvious kind of ROIC
model, return on invested capital. So,
if you make this sort of an investment,
you have significant demand for that
compute infrastructure, you're very good
at running the compute infrastructure,
that capital can deliver massive profit
returns for you with very high
confidence in some forecasted period.
Building the most advanced frontier
lab-driven model
also takes tens of billions of dollars
of capital. And the question really is,
can you deliver the profits from the
model?
And in a world where open source is
becoming so good and open weight models
are catching up so quickly, and all the
frontier labs are catching up to each
other so quickly, does it really make as
much sense to deploy tens of billions of
dollars against building a model? And I
think that the scientists that we're
seeing transition out are the scientists
that have been at the core of model
development, of making these frontier
models. And they were certainly first
out the gate.
You can look at some of the early
interviews with Jeff Dean from a couple
years ago where they actually had a chat
GPT equivalent internally a year before
chat GPT came out from Open AI. Google
chose not to release it for fear of
cannibalizing search and so on. That's
when Sergey stepped in, and there was
this whole kind of revitalization. But
as time has gone on, and as everyone has
competed on models, as we've talked
about many times on the show, I think
it's pretty obvious that it is very hard
to get the same sort of return on
capital invested in model development as
it is in capital invested on compute
infrastructure and being model agnostic.
What Google has is probably one of the
greatest install enterprise bases in the
world for compute. They have the most
enterprise customers, they have the most
consumers, and in both cases, they don't
necessarily need to have the best model
to make an incredible business. They can
be model agnostic, they can work with
Anthropic, they can work with OpenAI,
they can work with SpaceX. They have a
significant ownership stake in SpaceX
and in Anthropic, and they can work with
all the open weights models, they can
host them all. So now, if you're one of
the great computer scientists, you're
Demis,
you're Jeff Dean, you're this whole
crew, and you're inside of Google and
they're allocating capital not to your
models, not to the things that you're
most interested in, but they're
allocating capital to infrastructure and
data centers and supporting the broad
ecosystem of models, you start to say,
"Well, given the fact that I can go down
the road and visit Brad Gerstner and a
couple other people and raise a couple
billion dollars at a multi-billion
dollar pre-money with a PowerPoint deck
because I'm the greatest in the world at
doing this,
that might be a better path for me."
>> Mhm.
>> And I think that that's the moment. So I
the way I would frame it is CapEx is
high alpha,
low beta in data center infrastructure,
that capital.
And model development theoretically
could be high alpha, but it's very high
beta. It's a very risky way to deploy
capital. So so if I'm the board, I'm the
management, I'm deploying more capital
in compute infrastructure, less capital
into model development. That's what I
think's going on.
>> Brad, what's your take on this?
>> I think David nails it. I mean, listen,
the same thing's going on at Microsoft,
right? Satya is out this week saying,
you know, citing Morgan Stanley's report
and saying they're seeing over a 30%
return on invested capital in tokens as
a service, right? So in the
infrastructure business. So I think
David's exactly right. Those are such
good businesses, right? You you you
deploy capital, everybody's renting it
from you, but the scientists who want to
be involved in super intelligence, who
want to cure cancer, who want to be on
the frontier of these models. Right?
They're sitting there dealing with this
channel conflict at Google because, you
know,
Google Cloud wants all of the compute in
order to rent it out to Anthropic, and
those those building the frontier models
internally want that compute in order to
compete with Anthropic. So, you have
this inherent channel conflict between
those wanting to build the models. I
think David said it really well. Um and
I think that's a that that's a big
challenge for them. It looks like it's
being resolved in favor of being more of
an infrastructure company. So, where
does, you know, telescope out for a
second? SpaceX also reported this week.
They also have channel conflict. They're
renting out their compute to Anthropic
at the same time they're trying to build
their own model with Grok and Cursor.
You have that channel conflict at
Google. You have that channel conflict
at Microsoft, although I don't even
really see them pushing the frontier
anymore in terms of models. Meta's
talking about getting into the
infrastructure as a service game. And
then at Anthropic and OpenAI, you don't
have any of that channel conflict. They
say, "We're not in the infrastructure
business. We're only in the model
business." So, I think it's a, you know,
a clarifying view as we look forward
that we may in fact not have those
companies on the frontier of model
development if all these people leave.
>> By the way, thanks to the law passed on
CapEx depreciation, if you assume a 26%
corporate tax rate,
every dollar you deploy in CapEx because
you get to write it off in this year,
you're basically getting 26% off.
You know, that's money you get right
back.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Hey, Sachs, let me have you
comment on this as well, Polymarket,
which companies will have the number one
AI model by the end of this year on
December 31st. Um now, of course, in the
last time they did this, Anthropic won,
so they're not on the list. They're the
winner. But who will have it going
forward? OpenAI 32%, Google 20%, Alibaba
14%. And then you got Moonshot, xAI,
Meta, ByteDance, all All about 10% So
Sachs, your thoughts here on what's the
better business?
Is the better business being in the
language model frontier model or is that
getting quickly commoditized and really
you want to be in the token sale
business or is that also going to be a
commodity and you just need to be on the
application layer?
>> Here's what I think is going on in terms
of the the market structure is when I
saw this Google news,
my reaction was and then there were two.
Because like Brad was saying, we used to
have five major companies in the hunt to
be the leading frontier lab, the leading
frontier model just a year ago. Now
we're really down to just Anthropic and
Open AI. So, the market for frontier
intelligence has become a duopoly. Now,
Elon is still in the hunt. I'm sure
Google would say they're still on the
hunt. But like Brad is saying, they may
have contradictory incentives there.
Because they can actually do quite well
just with their compute.
So, I think that the market for frontier
intelligence has become a duopoly. I
think it's a very powerful duopoly.
I don't think it's being commoditized. I
think that what we're evolving to is a
two-tier market structure where there's
a market for frontier intelligence and
there's a market for let's call it kind
of commodity or lagging intelligence,
whatever you want to call it that's 6 to
12 months behind. There is a market for
those tokens, those models. But the
reality is you can't charge anything for
the weights. You can charge for the
compute. You can charge for the
inference that you're providing. You can
charge for essentially consulting
services to help put the whole thing
together.
But if you're not at the frontier, you
can't charge for the model layer itself.
If you are at the frontier, you can
charge a premium. And that's where
Anthropic and Open AI are. And I think
the proof for this is just you look at
the growth rates of these companies. The
latest we heard is Anthropic is now over
80 billion of ARR. Started the year at
10.
It had forecast a 100 billion as exit
ARR for the year, and most people said
that that would be impossible to
achieve. Now, it looks like they're
going to do it with a couple of months
to spare. So, their estimates are going
up. I mean, 110, 120, or higher for end
of year ARR. OpenAI seeing acceleration.
So, I think what you're seeing now is a
very clear bifurcation of the market.
You've got a frontier model duopoly that
can charge a premium. I think of it like
Apple.
You know, Apple's competing against
Android. It's open-source.
Android actually has more users in the
world, but all the monetization goes to
Apple because people are willing to pay
for the premium experience.
I think in a similar way, people are
willing to pay a premium for true
frontier intelligence. If it's really at
the leading edge. But, if you're not the
leading edge, there's a huge market for
that, too. But, it's highly
commoditized. People are just willing to
pay you for the compute. So, I mean,
that's what I see happening right now.
>> Jason, what do you think? Jason, what do
you think?
>> Uh well, if you look at Google Cloud,
they posted 82% year-over-year revenue
growth, which is uh something we've
never seen uh in the history of these
cloud providers. Elon Musk and xAI just
had the SpaceX earnings. We're going to
get into that, but they also had massive
uptick in their Elon web services, as
I've dubbed it. And if you look at
Google, I still think Google will be the
number one uh AI company because they
have so many people using AI inside of
their products already.
They have five products now with over 3
billion monthly users each. Android
Search, Gmail, Chrome, YouTube all have
over 3 billion. If you've used any of
these products recently, uh they are
becoming AI-first products. YouTube
especially, but obviously Chrome and
Gmail, you're seeing um tools pop up
there for AI. And then,
Freeberg, you kind of alluded to this.
They have 13 products total with over a
billion, and that now includes Gemini.
In Q2, Gemini had over 950 monthly
active users, tripling year-over-year.
They will be the number one AI company
in terms of consumer usage, by far, I
think, this year. That doesn't mean that
the
frontier models are not great
businesses. They obviously are, but I
have been using exclusively non-frontier
models, and for 95% of the jobs I'm
doing, Sachs,
it's good enough. And I just posted
about this, you know, and Elon and I got
into it a little bit here, and I think
you referenced this in our group chat. I
I tweeted just the other day the
difference between the open-source
models I'm using and frontier is
negligible already. I believe that to be
a true statement for the work I'm doing,
and he said, Elon responded back to me,
it's actually a world of difference.
You know, if you're
doing something other than making a copy
of a video game, or you have incredible
speed needs, the frontier models are not
necessary anymore. They're just not
necessary. The people using the frontier
models are doing it because their
company set it up, and they it's too
hard to implement open-source right now,
but it's going to get easier and easier
to implement it. So, I'm still going
with open-source and Gemini being the
leaders in this space.
>> it it it's true for your use cases that,
let's say, the cheaper commodity
intelligence, that middle of the market
is good enough. Look, an Android phone
would be good enough for me. I could get
by on a cheap Android phone. You know
what? I still pay a premium for this
because I use it so much. So, if you're
a business that, let's say, you are a
hedge fund, and you're in a highly
competitive industry, you don't want to
take the chance that you're not getting
the best intelligence to power your
models, you know? And there's a lot of
industries like that where the
competitive dynamics will drive you to
pay for the best intelligence. There's
also situations, this goes back to the
blog post that Decagon posted, which is
if you're looking for use cases, you
also want to use the True Frontier.
Because again, when you're dealing with
immature use cases, you don't know where
the value is going to be and you're
searching for opportunity to use AI, you
just want to use the best. Because
again, the return on finding those use
cases is going to be so much greater
than the small premium you're paying at
the token level. So, I think there's a
lot of examples like that when, you
know, the use case
where you're in a competitive industry,
where you're just deploying AI, you want
the convenience of the full stack.
>> go Frontier model to summarize your
>> again, you know, unless your employees
are doing something stupid, like you
create a leaderboard and they're token
maxing, I don't think the cost is that
great. And again, the benefit that
you're getting is huge. So, a lot of
people just like, give me the best. I'm
willing to pay a premium for the best.
>> I'll take a slightly different take. I
think that it's not necessarily do you
take the best model or the open source
model. I think that there's a blend
that's happening. At least that's what I
see. For example, we'll use open source,
open weights for a vast majority of
simple workflow applications. But when
it comes to specialized applications,
where we really need to have
high-quality model proficiency, for
example, in life sciences, in genomics
modeling, I am going to go for the
premium model. If I'm working at a media
company and I'm trying to do AI
rendering of video, I'm going to use
Gemini's model that does video. It is
the best model or Sora or whatever the
best model is for that particular
application. So, I think the idea that
there's kind of a model that you pick
for everything, I think is the false
assumption. On the consumer side, it is
likely the case that the consumers are
not going to be using some open weight
model because they can pay 20-40 bucks a
month and get ChatGPT or Gemini or
Claude and be very happy paying 40 bucks
a month and they'll basically be able to
minimize their cost to run that for
consumers. For enterprise, I think the
enterprise is going to be very active in
selecting a blend of models that are
going to make the most sense. Very cheap
open weight model for simple workflow
applications, individual employees
spinning up an app, whatever, and then
more complex models for those really key
workflow tasks, and then specialized
models. And I will say it is way too
early to count Gemini out on building
incredible specialized models. They have
the best video data, they have the best
life sciences data, they've been working
on this for far longer than Anthropic or
OpenAI on the life sciences side.
They're very well ahead on that front. I
mean, Demis is still going to be running
Isomorphic Labs. So, when it comes to
these specialized models, verticalized
specialized models like video, life
sciences, protein folding, I think these
are the things where you're really going
to see Gemini shine. And then every
enterprise is going to have a mixture.
But hey, if you can be the cloud service
provider with that mixture of models,
which is what Google GCP can now be, I'm
going to sign up for working with GCP
versus working just with Anthropic.
>> One of the things this has created is
downward pressure on the pricing. We saw
OpenAI and Claude
do massive price cuts for tokens, so
they are reacting, they're not taking it
sitting down. And the orchestration
between these models is being built into
a lot of furnaces
inside of enterprises. So, what's your
take on the downward pressure on token
pricing, or is this just great for
consumers and enterprises cuz we've got
massive competition?
>> That's the thing. America's winning.
It's exactly what you want. We have
massively competitive market. We have
Chinese open source, domestic open
source, frontier national labs that are
doing what they're doing. We have
downward pressure on pricing. You know,
David referenced the duopoly. You know,
I think it's hard to call it a duopoly
when you're, you know, only a few years
into this and you have giants like
Amazon, Microsoft, and Google. I do
think he's right. I do think they've
emerged, you know, as the pure plays.
Their revenues would suggest that
they're, you know, they're gaining share
of wallet. But there are two points I
want to make here, because I think
they're non-consensus views that were
spoken this week. One was Elon's
response to you, Jason. Right? Over the
last 2 weeks, everybody's been saying
that the Chinese have caught up, that
open-source tokens have caught up in
intelligence, that they're much cheaper,
et cetera. And Elon comes out and says,
"Not so fast. We're entering the
singularity, and the frontier models are
way further ahead than people think." I
believe that to be true. I think for
your use case, they're very similar, but
I don't think that's the most
sophisticated use case that people are
trying to train on and trying to
experience. And then Jensen came out
this week and said, "Closed models are
actually cheaper." You know, if you
don't have to build it for yourself, if
you don't have to
you know, the training costs and a lot
of expertise to fine-tune and maintain
and guardrail and keep it safe. So, he's
basically making the argument that not
only are the the the frontier models
further ahead, but that the cost
differential between the two is not what
everybody's making it out to see to be,
which I think explains why they continue
to run away with it on the revenue side
of the equation. Um, but I think we have
healthy competition. I you're right, J
Cal. You know, for the vast majority of
use cases, I think token consumption is
going up for the open-source guys, while
share of economics is going up for the
frontier labs. I think that's what we
want to see.
>> Yeah, and it's just Android versus
iPhone all over again. One platform
makes the profit, one gets the majority
of users, at least globally in usage.
Uh, or let's suck SpaceX here. Uh, they
had their first earnings report as a
public company. Shares dropped 13%
uh, I think because people were a little
concerned about the surging AI capex.
It's down 30% since going public in
June, but it's now trading at it seems
to have settled in at a 1.4
trillion-dollar valuation. Went public
obviously above 2 trillion. Q2 results
were uh, spectacular. That is the only
way to put it. 7.8 billion in revenue,
up 92%
year-over-year. Let that sink in.
And 67% quarter-over-quarter. AI
revenue, Elon web services, more than
tripled quarter-over-quarter
to $2.6 billion. That's not cursor. That
hasn't closed yet. But that's going to
be one of the great purchases in
history. This is from Elon web services
renting out compute specifically to
Anthropic and Google from the Colossus
collection of servers.
But CapEx was up 18.4 billion in the
quarter. That's 6x year-over-year.
Obviously, you can do the math there for
a run rate of about 75
billion dollars. I'll stop there and get
your reaction, Brad, to the SpaceX IPO.
I know you've been tracking this and
commented on it heavily.
>> I mean, listen. I think that what First,
let's start off. $1.4 trillion
of value creation for this company is
extraordinary. So, the fact that from
peak to trough it's down 40 or 50% from
the IPO. We had that chart out a few
weeks ago. Remember that within 6 months
of the IPO, almost all these tech stocks
are down 50% peak to trough. We see it
again here with SpaceX. I thought it was
a really solid quarter. I thought his
guides were pretty extraordinary. 100
billion in ARR by the end of the year.
And he pulled forward the $1 trillion
target in ARR by a year from 2031 to
2030. Now, to just put that in
perspective, Morgan Stanley's 2030
revenue estimate is 325 billion, which
is also extraordinary. Remember, this
company did 18 billion in revenue last
year. So, whether you're taking Morgan
Stanley's numbers or Elon's numbers,
clearly the market is not pricing that
in. At 2 trillion, we were pricing ahead
a couple years. I think now it's you
know, the the value reflects kind of
where we are. The market has questions
about a few things. Here's what they
are. Number one, on the rental business,
the rental of compute business. He
rented out a huge block of compute to
Anthropic. It's the question that we've
been talking about here. Are you going
to use the compute to build your own
frontier model or you going to rent it
out? And if you rent it out, are you
going to be able to find those people
who have the capital to off-take that
compute? He's talking enormous numbers,
10 to 20 gigs, and people are wondering
how they're going to be able to finance
that. And remember those businesses, the
GPU rental businesses, tend to trade at
very low multiples. Look at CoreWeave,
etc. On the frontier model business, I
think this is the sleeper. I think he
said on the call that Grok tripled
tokens in the month of July. That
doesn't include Cursor. Cursor was
already on a path to go from 3 billion
to 10 billion by the end of the year.
Cursor plus Grok could be at 10 to 20
billion by the end of the year. That
would be an extraordinarily valuable
asset going to trade at a much higher
multiple than the data center business.
And then, of course, we haven't even
talked about Starlink and what he's
going to do,
uh, you know, I think going to run the
table on mobile. So, this is the normal
consolidation. We have funds like, uh,
uh, across Silicon Valley that are
distributing their shares. The stock is
traded down a bit, nothing surprising to
me here. Now, it's all about execution.
I think the most important thing to
watch, the two most important things to
watch are number one, how do the Grok
and Cursor revenues end the year?
>> Mhm.
>> And number two, um, you know, the
traction they get on, um, you know,
continuing to replace traditional mobile
carriers with Starlink.
>> The distribution started, I think, today
or yesterday. I got my first
distribution from a fund I'm in. I'm in
a couple of funds that are in SpaceX.
Seems like everybody's in that. And that
will obviously create downward pressure
if you are amongst the people who want
to cash out and have been in it for a
long time, but I'm holding these for my
grandkids. Sacks, your take on these
spectacular, yeah, I guess, is the only
way to describe them, results coming
from a vertical that wasn't part of
SpaceX's business but 9 months ago.
>> Yeah, look, I thought it was a very
bullish earnings call. I was a little
bit surprised that the stock went down
after the earnings call because not only
was it a beat and raise, but also I
think Elon spoke to a lot of their
plans. And the only thing I would add to
to what Brad said was around Starship.
Elon basically said, we all saw it,
right? That the Starship test flight was
successful. That Starship's floating in
the ocean. The heat shield worked.
That's going to enable more flights of
Starship now at a more accelerated rate.
That paves the way for the V3 satellite,
which enables much more bandwidth for
the Starlink network, which then powers
the whole direct-to-cell play. So, you
had that piece of it. I mean, just the
whole telecom aspect seemed very on
track and they're very bullish about
that. And then you've got the whole AI
data center play. Now, on the data
centers, I think what they said is that
they expect it to go from 1.4
gigawatts of compute to about two by the
end of the year.
And Elon said that the spot price for
computes in the $30 per watt range. So,
you know, you do the math. A gigawatt is
a billion watts. So, $30
per watt means 30 to 50 billion per
gigawatt. And I think they're at the
high end of that range right now. So,
when Elon says, "Look, we're going to
end the year at 100 billion of ARR," all
you have to believe is that they're at
two gigawatts of compute running for $50
a watt to hit that. That doesn't include
Starlink or the launch business or the
Grok cursor piece or any of these
things. So, I think that's why they're
so optimistic.
>> ways to win is what you're saying, Zach.
There's multiple ways to win with this
stock.
>> I think Starlink's just an unbelievable
juggernaut cash machine. If you look at
the financials, their segment reports
space, connectivity, and AI.
And on the connectivity side, the
Starlink side, it they generated $2.6
billion in adjusted EBITDA. You can kind
of approximate that to be
kind of operating cash flow.
Space was kind of, you know, negative
200 million, so call it break even, and
AI was plus 1.1 billion. But AI, to
Brad's point, it's unclear whether the
pricing they're getting on compute
rental today is temporary and at a
premium because of the lack of compute
available in the market today, and
people that need computer paying Elon a
premium for that Cuban Q. So, I think
there's a question mark where that goes.
But the connectivity piece on Starlink,
4.3 billion in the quarter,
and 2.6 billion in adjusted EBITDA. He's
got 12 million subscribers, that's
doubled year-over-year.
$66 ARPU per month, uh what people are
paying per month.
And he grew 20% quarter over quarter.
So, if you extrapolate this out, he's
pretty close to being at a 24 million
subscriber run rate on this multiple,
and assuming this enterprise stuff,
which is like airlines and other things
scale, which they seem to be scaling
with the consumer business,
Starlink alone
could be generating on the order of 40
billion dollars of revenue top line with
a huge amount of that flowing to free
cash. That could be a 30 billion dollar
free cash flow within the year.
That alone provides the cash flow to
fund much of what what Elon's doing. And
if you just put a 30X multiple on that,
which I think you can because these
subscription businesses are very high
renewal rate, very low CAC, I think he
could probably get a 30X just on the
Starlink business. The Starlink business
alone could be a trillion dollar market
cap within 2 years, within 18 months,
let's say. That I think funds all of the
rest of this is kind of science projects
and upside. So, I'm kind of making a
bull case. It's crazy to me how well the
Starlink business performs, and you can
see it in AT&T and Verizon, HughesNet,
ViaSat. I mean, these companies have
been decimated. I used to have a
HughesNet satellite dish on my Sonoma
County ranch in order to get internet,
that's what we had to use. It was like,
you know, 200 bucks a month or
something.
>> Terrible, cuz those are high orbit,
right? And they take forever to
>> Terrible service. And that market got
decimated by Starlink. And if he
launches the handset thing, that
subscriber growth is going to go right
now he's adding 2 million subscribers on
the consumer side a quarter. You could
see that going to 4 to 5 million a
quarter. You could actually see an
acceleration in the consumer
subscriptions.
>> mobile subs 400 million mobile subs just
in the United States.
>> I think you can make you can make the
bull case on Starlink alone. And then
the rest of it is like, hey, is Elon
going to do well with investing the
excess capital that's spinning off of
Starlink? How is Elon going to do with
that money? Well, I don't know who else
I give it to
>> [laughter]
>> to like, you know, do what he's doing
with Starship and with AI compute and
the terrafab.
>> Oh my god, this is the science fiction
uh story of
Starlink County, Texas.
>> how the US gets off of this dependency
with Taiwan and China from
semiconductors, if Elon takes this on
his shoulders and he delivers what he's
showing as a vision here today, this is
going to be the greatest semiconductor
fabrication site on planet Earth.
>> Well, you know, I I would say something,
you know, David, to your point. You know
how many CEOs or founders would just
take that Starlink business, which is
such an exceptional business,
m- trillion-dollar business going to 2
trillion, and they would not take any of
these other risks.
They would not do terrafab, they would
not try to build out the data center,
they would not try to build their own
model. That's highly risky, but highly
important investments that are being
made. I mean, it is heroic and important
that we have this level of I just think
unbridled enthusiasm for innovation uh
on the frontier that Elon's doing, and I
wish we saw more CEOs, more public
companies willing to take this level of
risk. We just got done talking about,
you know, some CEOs maybe that were
taking less risk because the safe bet
was was easier to make. Elon refuses
just to take the safe bet. He's taking
all the dollars from this thing where he
has an extraordinary business and
plowing them back into these things that
are critically important to the United
States.
>> And by the way, Brad, that's such a good
point because if you look at other CEOs
and other management teams, they're
getting in on this. They're starting to
realize that buying back your shares,
giving dividends is not as important as
betting on the future. DoorDash got
taken to the woodshed because they're
investing too much in capex. Obviously,
Google got smacked with their capex
spend. So, that keeps happening over and
over again. And just on the headwinds
that SpaceX is going to face, the
arguments that I think will turn out to
be wrong, but they're valid to talk
about here are, "Hey, is this demand for
tokens and compute going to keep up or
does on-prem and desktops and
open-source models getting smaller,
better? Does that actually mute at some
point demand?" I don't think it does. I
don't know there's an upper
Uh I don't know if there's an upper
bound for on-demand intelligence. The
second one, obviously, is Starlink is
for people who are in a rural
neighborhood. If you've got Verizon
fiber to your building or Spectrum,
you're not putting, nor can you put, a
Starlink on your building. So, the piece
there that's going to be um
uh explained probably in the next year
or two is every single Tesla sold is
going to have Starlink in it. When they
get that merger done, what that means is
you're going to have Wi-Fi networks uh
connecting any phone
to any Tesla, say all those robo-taxis
out there, you'll be able to connect
also directly with the next generation
of Starlink. So, your phone will be able
to direct if it's got clear line of
sight, it's going to be able to connect
to any Tesla on the road, which there
are many, that all future ones will have
a Starlink built into them. So, those
are super promising. And then finally,
you know, there's been a lot of
speculation about the valuation. Brad,
you brought it up. I think that
liquidity when people were asking you
and I heard you talk about it, hey,
private companies, venture capital, we
are a voting mechanism, and then when it
goes public, it becomes a weighing
mechanism, and sometimes you'll have
this moment in time
where there's hand-wringing about those
valuations, and the hand-wringing peaked
in the last quarter. You had 160 times
uh price-to-sales ratio for Tesla when
it first came out. 160 times, right? You
You take their This two or three
trillion-dollar market cap,
and you put it against a smaller revenue
number. Well, if you look at the revenue
number increasing, now we're down to a
45 times price-to-sales ratio. So, some
kind of uh balance is occurring here.
Yeah, Brad, between these private and
public markets, as well as the increase
in revenue.
>> Yeah, I I I mean, honestly, I think this
is all super healthy.
I think the SpaceX IPO was
extraordinary. I think the consolidation
here is perfectly predictable. And now
you have a company at 1.4 trillion that
I think if you take a three-year or a
four-year view,
you can see yourself tripling your money
in this business at a very reasonable
valuation on the Morgan Stanley numbers
or on the Elon numbers or whatever, but
that's always been the bet. Do you
believe that Elon is the greatest
innovator and a great allocator of
capital? But the price of entry matters,
right? When you get carried away on day
one of an IPO, and you buy this thing
over two trillion, you got to know that
this is going to happen. I was on CNBC
the day of the IPO, and I said I would
want to own this company, but I'm not
sure today's the day I would buy the
company. Right? And so, I you know,
>> Entry price matters. I mean, this is
just a fundamental.
>> but let me give you another one, you
know, like we've talked about the
Anthropic IPO, or a lot of people have
talked about it later this year. I hear
a lot of people saying 1.5 or 2 trillion
dollars. David just talked earlier that
it's going to be run rating over 100
billion maybe by the end of the year.
That's like 10 to 15 times revenue. That
is not that much for a company that just
grew 10 X and is rumored to be
profitable in Q2. And so I look at the
market, the consolidation we saw in the
month of July, you know, we put in the
Leopold bottom hopefully in July that,
you know, a lot of semi stocks were
down. And I literally bought the bottom.
Hey, hey, listen, the guy's doing great.
He He's apparently still up 80% for the
year, just made another big private
investment. I I I I think he's done an
extraordinarily good job building a firm
in a short period of time. But the
market did panic around that.
As as as he had to cover I think all of
that is really good. So as I look ahead
marching to these IPOs later in the year
on the back of the SpaceX IPO, I think
we're in in in really good shape.
You know, particularly if these revenues
continue a pace.
>> You know what Elon's really good at is
just
building stuff.
Like
>> Yeah.
>> Factories, physical
physical physical sites. That is such a
core advantage in this world where
everyone's competing for data centers
and fabs. The software layer needs
hardware in the physical world in order
to deliver their software services. And
there is no one better than Elon at
actually doing that. Look at how
gigafactories have been stood up around
the world. This is his core competency.
So Brad, like when you put Elon up
against a Dario and a Sam and even an
Alphabet which has 27 years of doing
this
I mean, man, Elon's got a core advantage
if this is what this world comes down
to.
>> He said something like that on the call
where he said, "Look, putting up data
centers is nothing compared to the
difficulty of putting up a rocket,
right? It's like, you know, creating
data centers is not rocket science." So
they take some of those hardware
expertise that they have from SpaceX and
they put them into data centers and
that's why they've been able to stand up
you know, more data centers or or bigger
data centers faster than all the
competitors. A couple points there. Is
it clear why Starship is so important to
Starlink? Okay, let me just explain this
quickly. So, basically
SpaceX has developed a new V3 satellite
that has 10x the bandwidth of its V2
satellite. So, currently the Starlink
network is powered by V2 satellites.
They deploy them on the Falcon 9 rocket
and they launch about 27 satellites per
launch and that adds about 2.6 terabits
per second of total network capacity.
Starship deploys 60 of these V3
satellites per launch. That would add 60
terabits per second of total network
capacity per launch. So, over 20 times
more capacity per launch. That's the
power of it. So, if they get Starship
working. By the way, the last test, not
only did it prove that the heat shield
worked, my understanding is they
actually launched or rather they
deployed 20 V3 satellites as a test.
And they were able to make connection
with those satellites and prove that it
worked.
>> They even had cameras on them. The
reason we were able to see the Starship
was because they're like, "YOLO, let's
put some cameras HD cameras on them."
>> Right. Now, I think those satellites
basically was just a test and they They
burned They burned up. So, I think the
next big milestone here will be when
they launch Starship with, let's say, 60
of these V3 satellites, put them in the
correct orbit, make connection with
them, add the bandwidth to the network.
That's going to be a big milestone. But,
you play this out to its logical
conclusion and the bandwidth available
to the Starlink network goes up 10x or
eventually 100x times and that's when
they can do all the interesting things
like direct to cellular. There were some
interesting hints that Gwynne Shotwell
talked about about with ground stations
about what they could potentially do
there.
>> And I think I think they might buy
T-Mobile or something like that, Sachs.
It's easily within their range of
purchases.
>> And and I think Elon mentioned something
about potentially the the Starlink
network could eventually handle roughly
half
of internet traffic.
So, I mean, this this thing could get so
much bigger than just 12 million
subscribers to your point, Freeberg. But
look, I I want to actually talk about
the data centers for a second, Brad. I I
do have a couple of questions about
this. So,
Elon mentioned that, okay, we're going
to be at 2 gigawatts by the end of the
year. He said that we will be at 5 to 10
next year, closer to 10 than 5. So,
let's just say 8, okay? So, I'm just
making that up, but it's in their range.
So, let's just say that's an add of 6
gigawatts. So, they go
from 2 to 8. Okay? To me, there's two
questions there. One is, how do you know
that the spot price is going to stay
where it is? You know, can it stay at
$50
per watt? How do we know? How do we
track that? How much risk is there
around that? I got the sense
on the call that Elon thinks that number
is going up because the market is memory
constrained right now. I think he
mentioned that we might see a 20%
increase in memory production next year,
but the demand is going up 200% plus.
So, the market is constrained by
whatever the bottleneck is at that time.
Right now, the bottleneck is memory. So,
where do you see the spot price going?
How do we know? How much risk is there
around that? And then, the other
question I would have is if you go from
2 to 8
gigawatts, that you have net of 6. We
know that a gigawatt power data center
is, you know, 50 billion of CapEx.
>> Right.
>> So, 6 incremental gigawatts of compute
would be 300 billion of CapEx next year.
Assuming they build that, right? I mean,
they have optionality around that, I'm
sure. So, how do you finance that? You
know, what's the most non-dilutive way?
They said their payback is a year or
less. I'm sure that's tied to the spot
price. So, you only have to finance it
for a year, and the question is, do you
think Nvidia gives them that financing
or how will this play out, I guess is my
question.
>> It's a great framing, David. First,
it's $50 billion per gigawatt to build
minimum. Okay, so you're $300 billion.
So, in order to finance that, it seems
to me you either have to go into the
market and borrow the money
or you have to do a dilutive equity
raise, neither of which they want to do.
Um or you get Nvidia to backstop it.
Um which they've indicated that they're
going to do more but the problem there
is Nvidia shareholders don't want them
backstopping unlimited because the fear
in the world is that that sprite spot
price at some point, right, may go
against you and when it does, the
payback period changes. Now, nobody
thinks that the payback period is going
to be 1 year even though the spot price
is suggesting that it is that today,
right? Just a few years ago, people
thought you would get paid or not few
years ago, few months ago, people
thought you'd get payback over 4 years.
So, you basically spend 50,
you then earn 10 to 15 per year,
you get payback over 4 to 5 years and
then hopefully you get the 6th year
which really takes you up well above 20%
in terms of your returns. Um right now,
the shortage is so acute
and the willingness to pay from the
front frontier labs is so high because
they all recognize they're on the verge
of some massive breakthroughs that
they're willing to pay three, four, five
X market pricing in order to get at
scale compute. And that's what happened
with the Anthropic deal with SpaceX. I
think Anthropic would buy a lot more of
that today if they could. Same with
OpenAI.
>> You're saying, Brad, they would be
willing to overpay by a factor of up to
five X.
>> Well, that's the 50 that you know,
that's the $50 per watt that David was
referencing. They would be willing to
pay this 30 to 50 if they could get at
scale compute that would give them a
competitive advantage over the other
people in the market. And remember,
there aren't a lot of people who have
the off-take revenue that can afford to
buy compute at this scale, right? It
wasn't the Chinese open source companies
that were buying, you know, SpaceX's
excess computer, building the 10
gigawatt you know, plant in in Ohio.
That's OpenAI and Anthropic. So, the
vast majority of the off-take
commitments are coming from Anthropic,
OpenAI, and Nvidia, right? When you hear
about the hyperscalers building all of
this out
you know, this computer out they're
building it out to sell to the people
that we you know, that we just
mentioned. So, David, net net if he
builds 6 gigawatts next year, and by the
way, probably only Elon,
you know, can actually stand up that
much in that time frame. Like Jensen
said to me on the pod, it's like nobody
comes close. Microsoft doesn't come
close, you know, Google doesn't come
close in terms of standing it up in that
time frame.
Um I think that he's going to have a
challenge, you know, getting all of the
componentry, right? I know he can stand
it up, but can he get the memory? Can he
get the chips? Can he get the land power
shell all in time? I think the off-take
is there.
Right? But to put it in perspective,
this year Anthropic and OpenAI combined,
their starting total compute was like 5
gigawatts.
So, he's talking about incrementally
adding more than they had as combined
companies, right?
>> that much of an increase when Anthropic
is growing 10x year over year, and
OpenAI is maybe at what, 4x or maybe
higher now?
>> The demand exists in the world. The
demand exists in the world today. I
think it will exist in the world for
well, you know, the next 12 to 24
months, but there is a wall of worry in
the market. The reason we saw the
pullback in July is Kimmy scared people
into thinking, "Oh my gosh, they're
going to undercut the Frontier's
revenues." And if they undercut the
Frontier Labs revenues, who the hell is
going to pay for all this compute?
That's why you saw a 40% trade down in
the CoreWeaves of the world and you
know, the the all of the the
semiconductor stocks and semiconductor
related AI stocks.
>> ways, the fact that there's a discussion
going on that this next 10 gigawatts is
going to cost, you know, a Sachs $500
and you ask the question, where does
that come from? A secondary offering?
Does Nvidia put it on their books? Do
they create SPVs off their books like
some people are doing? You know, the
fact that we're having this
conversation, everybody's aware of it,
the market has been educated on it means
I think people will be able to change in
real time if it doesn't come to pass or
if it slows down, which I suspect this
cannot keep up at this pace, you know,
more than another two years or so.
>> Although
as our good friend Bill Gurley likes to
remind us, he's like, I can't believe
that we're all just taking in stride
this level of seller financing. Right?
He would call it circular revenues,
right? But the market has gotten
comfortable with this. And remember,
like we saw in July, if there is a scare
about demand, the whole sector trades
down.
>> Yeah.
>> Everything will trade down, you know,
together because that's just the
leverage that you're pumping into the
system. You're effectively backstopping
people's ability to build ahead of their
revenue. So, it becomes much more
violent if you ever see demand slippage.
Um, you know, famous last words, I don't
see it today over the course of the next
12 to 18 months. Um, but you know, you
have these unknown unknown moments that
certainly causes people to be fearful.
Credit spreads are blowing, you know,
have continued to to stay wide on these
deals. So, there is fear in the market
about them.
>> All right, everybody, the fifth annual
If it's September, you know, it's time
for the All-In Summit. The fifth annual
is happening. Yes, that's right. Uh,
David Friedberg's been at work and we
have an all-star all-star
list of people joining us. Jensen Huang,
founder and CEO of Nvidia. If you care
about where AI is heading, you won't
want to miss this conversation.
>> The best. The Oracle.
>> Satya Nadella, CEO of Microsoft, fan of
the pod, will be coming on for the
second time. Jared Isaacman from NASA,
the one the only Brad Gerstner, and Bill
Gurley, BG2, coming back. SpaceX's
Gwynne Shotwell, my guy Jake Paul,
Nick Shirley,
a lot of incredible people coming.
Martin Shkreli maybe is even coming.
He's That's going to be fun. Go to the
allin summit.com to apply today.
allin.com or the allinsummit.com. Any of
those will get you there. And
we're taking over Universal Studios
again. We'll have our own private
playground. Dave Friedberg, great job on
the summit. Casino night, too. Yeah,
it's going to be a big casino night.
>> Biggest yet. And the concert to be
announced who will be performing at the
concert, but it is going to be
incredible. So, I'll just say one of the
things about the summit, we've had
people come to the summit from over 60
countries. It's really incredible to
meet all these people, entrepreneurs,
investors, people that are just really
interested in the topics that we talk
about. We try and have the world's most
important conversations, but it's really
this amazing community experience.
That's what brings folks back. So, we
try and invest more and more every year
in making it an amazing experience, not
just cool content on a stage, which I
think is what a lot of these other shows
really deliver, but it's like, how do
you actually come and have a have an
experience for a couple days? It's going
to be awesome. So, we're excited.
>> it is those three things that we focus
on. One, you're going to learn
something, right? You got these great
people you're going to learn something
from them. You're going to meet new
people, you're going to network, and
then you're going to have these great
experiences. It's the trifecta, folks.
You excited, Brad? You excited to be
back? What What are the dates? What are
the dates again?
Look at your calendar. You're speaking.
>> September 13th through 15th in LA.
>> This couldn't be better dates for the
summit. I mean, we're we're going to be
within 60 days of an election, midterm
election. We're going to be within 30
days of an IPO, you know, potentially of
Anthropic. I mean, like
it it's going to be heated. The
SaaS-pocalypse,
not the SaaS-pocalypse, this is the
SaaS-pocalypse is
I guess winding its way out. The
indigestion might be clearing. Airtable
just got acquired for less than it
raised. It's a profitable SaaS company,
a great product, $480 million half a
billion dollars in annual revenue,
growing 20% a year, respectable if it
was a public company, with almost a
billion dollars in cash has been sold.
It's been sold for 1.28 billion, about
10% of its peak valuation, which was
11.7 billion in 2021. Now, they did have
a bunch of cash, so if you include the
cash position, sell was 2.25 billion.
They were acquired by a firm called
Bending Spoons. This is an Italian
company, Milan-based company. They buy
challenged but, you know, interesting
businesses, AOL's legacy business,
Evernote, Eventbrite, Vimeo, meetup.com.
And they just went public last month.
Shares, that is Bending Spoons, went
public last month. Shares are up 15% on
the Airtable news. Sax, when we look at
this, this was a company that had done a
lot of things right, had a massive
amount of cash in their war chest, but
rumors were maybe the founders were a
little exhausted, maybe some of the
investors were exhausted who bought in
at a high level. What can we take away
from this transaction in Bending Spoons?
Are they the buyer of last resort now?
>> Well, I think they're creating a great
business for themselves because I think
this will end up being a fairly
profitable acquisition for them. Let me
just add a piece to this, which is
Airtable spun out its AI agent business,
which is known as Hyperagent, into a
separate independent company prior to
this acquisition. So, I think what's
going on here is that the founders and
talent of the company, they said, "Look,
we don't want to have to make this
legacy product work that's basically a
private equity play. I'll explain what
that means in a second. We want to focus
on the new thing, the AI company, that's
where the big value creation's going to
be in the future or the potential for
it. So, essentially the talent is going
to focus on the venture play, and then
they're selling the private equity play
to Bending Spoons. Now, why do I think
this could be a good acquisition for
Bending Spoons? I think there was a
really interesting data point that I saw
in the commentary on this, which is only
30%
of Airtable's sales team was making
quota. They had a 30% sales attainment
number.
And that told me a lot about this
business, okay? What it told me is, and
I'm reading between the lines here,
but [snorts] this was a company that had
a successful PLG motion, in other words,
organic growth, product-led growth, and
they were growing about 20% a year. But,
that was not good enough for its board.
You know, these are investors, some of
whom invested in an $11 billion peak
valuation. So, they're looking for a
venture-type outcome. So, what happens?
The board pressures the founders to do
something that frankly is unnatural for
them, which is they say, "Look, you
should bolt on a traditional sales-led
motion here to get the growth up
faster."
Does that work? No, they probably get a
little bit of growth out of it, but they
only get 30% attainment. So, they've got
hundreds and hundreds of sales reps here
trying to push on a string, and it's not
making it grow faster. So, now, what's
the opportunity for the acquirer here?
Bending Spoons can go in here and do
what Elon did at Twitter, eliminate
85-90%
of the cost structure, don't do this
sales-led motion, just go back to your
product-led growth roots. You'll
probably keep most of that 20% growth,
and it'll be a very profitable company.
You'll be able to
>> 80% profitable probably, right?
>> Probably. I mean, people are saying to
the bottom line, pays the acquisition in
a couple years.
>> generate 30%
EBITDA margin. I think, like you're
saying, it could be 80, 90%. I don't
think you need to keep most of this
business or most of the cost structure
associated with this business.
Um Airtable is a company that has its
fans. Um I think they will probably
stick with it. And, you know, you'll
you'll be generating I don't know, you
could probably generate 300 million of
EBITDA a year or 400 million uh while
growing, you know, 10 to 20%. So, that's
the play for Bending Spoons. But, look,
that's
>> investors here, Sachs, they're happy to
get their money back and move on to the
next thing. It's a bit of a push for
them, you know, in terms of at the
blackjack table, rather than they've got
to go 10x just to catch up. And then
they would have to go 10x again to make
their LPs happy. It's not going to
happen.
>> I think the question is if Bending
Spoons can basically take this business
that's not making money and probably
generate 400 million a year of EBITDA
and pay for the acquisition in just 3
years.
>> Amazing.
>> Why isn't that something that the
company could do on its own? And I think
that's the structural problem is I think
it's very hard for both
VCs who are on the board and the
founders to shift into private equity
mode. Why? Because they're going to have
to demolition what they've built, right?
They've got all this loyalty to the
team. They don't want to think about how
do I eliminate 80, 90% of the cost
structure? It's just not what they do. I
mean, what Of course. What founders want
to do and and the outcome that the board
members are going for is a venture
backed outcome. And I think they could
have done this. They could do what
Bending Spoons does,
>> They're not built for it, Sachs.
>> built for it. And moreover, the
structure of the cap table is all wrong
because they're sitting behind this
giant liquidation preference. All these
investors have to get paid back who
invested at this $11 billion valuation
and and you know, all the way up.
>> The The incentives are broken, Brad. And
you you yourself at your firm Altimeter,
you were pretty frisky in this period.
You made a lot of bets. So, uh I don't
know if Air Table was one of them, uh
but you made some SaaS bets there. Some
of them were at high valuations. How are
you looking back at that time period?
Any lessons that you take going forward?
>> Multiples of revenue can compress very
quickly.
Right? It works great when the company's
growing greater than 50%, but remember
it's just a heuristic. It's just a very
rough estimate, used almost exclusively
in Silicon Valley. You know, so people
are saying, "Oh my god, this thing sold
for two times revenue." But when you
actually look at it on a look-through
basis, probably sold for maybe 30 times
free cash flow. I don't think it's easy
to get it to 400 million in EBITDA. I
think if it was, the board would have
done that. I'm you know, we're involved
in some of these companies. Once they
slow down, the company morale goes to
hell. Turnover among your customers, uh
you know, begins to spike. Um it starts
to feed on itself. So, I think it It
sucks to go
>> work every day.
>> Brad, what do you need to keep? What do
you need to keep? Okay, so look, think
about that.
>> I don't know the core product and what's
happening in terms of turnover in the
core product, David, but my hunch is
that the core product has started uh to
really
fizzle as the advances in the core
product has slowed down. You're seeing a
bunch of churn out of it on the product
side, and now people are saying,
"Listen, it's almost impossible for a
software company today to keep any
decent sales people, to keep any
different decent product development
people, cuz they all want to go work on
AI."
>> Agreed, but you don't need them for this
product.
>> I agree.
>> the market The market's being efficient.
I mean, look, this is where I think
Bending Spoons has an advantage that the
company's
board and founders wouldn't have, which
is they already have an infrastructure,
right? They have a core team at Bending
Spoons that's managing now, I don't
know, dozens of these properties. And
so, they can plug this in. I think AI in
a way makes their job easier, because in
the past, the reason why
>> you couldn't eliminate like all of the
talent, the infrastructure is because
you needed the institutional memory. You
needed people who knew the code base.
Now, AI can learn the code base
instantly, right?
>> That's an interesting insight.
>> And so, [clears throat] yeah, it's so
they
>> Maintaining is easier with AI.
>> I think maintenance mode becomes a way
easier with AI because you don't need
the historical knowledge anymore. The AI
can go in
>> And future of this.
>> reconstitute that that historical
knowledge.
>> Let me get you in here, Freebird, uh if
I may. Uh when you look at the lessons
from peak ZIRP and SaaS, and then we
look at, you know, this moment in time,
this surging AI market, any parallels
that we might find here, uh or lessons
uh between the two?
>> Between ZIRP and AI?
>> Era?
>> The ZIRP SaaS era, we had a lot of very
high valuations, a lot of enthusiasm, a
lot of suspending disbelief. We're here
in the AI era. We just talked about, you
know, the price of compute and all these
companies being at a 100x uh
price-to-sales ratio. Any parallels here
or not? It's a kind of a softball
question for you.
>> No, this is a very different paradigm.
Uh the AI capex buildout and model
training,
which is where the predominance of the
capital is flowing,
is not about some high multiple on
revenue, which is where capital was
flowing into SaaS. It's like, oh, you
get a 20x multiple, turn a dollar into
20, that's great, let's do it all day
long. This is a very different structure
and strategy and capital
um allocation process. So, I don't think
that I I would look at them as being
linked to the AI era.
>> question, to be honest. I was letting
you hit it out of the park.
>> Look, I mean, obviously SaaS companies
were overvalued during the ZIRP era for
two reasons. One is that we had
artificially low interest rates, so we
had a kind of a a speculative asset
super bubble. But, the other is that
people were treating these things like
guaranteed annuities, and actually
growing annuities. They'd look at it and
see, oh, 120% net dollar retention, so
this thing will just grow 20%
year-over-year forever as a base case,
right? And they would then price that
way. But what we've seen with AI is
obviously
there's disruption, and you can't To
Brad said, I'm sure they're seeing
elevated churn right now, and it's not
an annuity. Things can change. So
obviously now these things are trading
at a much greater discount. All of that
being said, let me just say I don't
think you can extrapolate to the entire
SaaS space based on this one company,
Airtable. I think there's some things
about Airtable that make it very
different than, I don't know, let's say
a Salesforce or a Workday is, you know,
Airtable was always a little bit of a
quirky product. I remember at the peak
hype for this company, people were
saying like, oh, this is like a new
Excel or a new Google Sheets.
>> New Microsoft Office, yeah.
>> Yeah, it was basically a spreadsheet for
words. That's how people were were
viewing it as this like this new kind of
spreadsheet for for words as opposed to
numbers. And it never achieved that kind
of promise. It never achieved that kind
of ubiquity. People understand how to
use spreadsheets. Everyone uses them.
Airtable never got to that point. Most
people still don't know what Airtable
is. It again, it had its dedicated fans,
but it was a hard product to explain to
people. When do you use it?
>> a cult following is what you're saying.
>> but it but it never it never achieved
that sort of level of acceptance. It was
never self-explanatory in terms of why
you should use it, what the use cases
are. They never were able to kind of get
the marketing right because of that.
>> And to be honest, if you look at Claude
CoWork, Perplexity AI, computer agents,
those things are now doing what Airtable
did. So
>> It never carved out, I think, a niche
where it was super clear when you were
always supposed to use Airtable. And and
really it was part of this hodgepodge of
of this grab bag, you should you could
say, of no-code tools. This is the
category it was put in. And no code has
to be the most impacted, the most
disrupted area of SaaS right now
because, I mean, what is Claude code
really good at? I mean, that's the
ultimate no code tool.
>> Lovable Claude code, Perplexity, all of
these
ones.
>> Yeah, the thing with Airtable or Retool,
things like this is it's true you didn't
need to be a coder to use them, but you
had to learn how to use Airtable. You
had to learn how to use Retool, all
these It was kind of these, you know,
alternative programming languages in a
way. And you just don't need to learn
any of that anymore. I mean, you use
Claude and you just tell it what you
want it to create. And so, you know, if
you do want to create a some sort of new
dashboard, some sort of, I don't know,
like a verbal spreadsheet or whatever,
you just tell Claude what you want. You
don't have this learning curve. Look,
all of SaaS is being impacted right now,
but this has got to be the most impacted
area. So, I don't know that you can
totally extrapolate based on what's
happening to Airtable. I don't
necessarily think that you want to
replace your CRM, your ERP, your HR
system with something that's been vibe
coded. You want the certainty, you know,
for anything that involves compliance.
>> I got to be honest. My team, Sachs,
made I don't Do you use like a portfolio
off-the-shelf SaaS tool for managing
crafts like um
uh portfolios and everything?
>> Well, we we vibe coded something
actually.
>> Okay, so yeah, we just did the same,
too. So, my team just built something
that is so mind-blowing that to buy it
with off-the-shelf software would have
been a quarter million dollars in
software and like a million dollars in
integration over two or three years, and
we built it in a month. And and now we
have complete insight into the whole
portfolio, the competitive set, the
founders, everything going on.
>> Keep in mind that one of the reasons why
Leopold got blown out, okay? I mean, it
it is because he bet on the SaaS
apocalypse. Remember, it wasn't just
that he was super long these chip stocks
that had a correction.
>> right? He was short SaaS?
>> He was short Adobe and a whole bunch of
other SaaS companies, and those trades
also moved the wrong way on him. So,
again, I just think that it's painting
with too broad a brush to say that all
of SaaS is going to get obliterated
here.
>> Yeah.
>> And there was a really good post about
this. Let me just quote from this where
they said
nobody buys Microsoft because Microsoft
writes the best code. They buy Microsoft
because Microsoft is the rail that
everything else runs on. Active
Directory is where your employee
identities live. Excel is where your
board decks numbers come from. Teams is
where the compliance recorded
conversation happens. Azure holds a
FedRAMP high authorization and
Department of Defense Impact Level 5
clearance, which means a defense
contractor cannot casually swap it out
for something cheaper, and so on down
the line. So, there's a lot of really
good compliance reasons why, if you're a
large enterprise, you're not going to
want to spend tens of millions of
dollars ripping out something that cost
you a million dollars a year. It just
that just doesn't make sense. And I
noticed that Benioff just tweeted 5
minutes ago that 15 out of 15 cabinet
agencies run on Salesforce. Look, the
government is not going to rip and
replace Salesforce with something
white-coded. So, look, not all SaaS is
equal in this dimension.
>> bought some Figma. I just think some of
these SaaS companies with great founders
who are in it for the long term, and
they have like passionate user bases, I
think they will make the jump to
AI-first products, and I I'd put Figma
in that bucket.
>> Just to wrap this this section.
>> IGV's up 20% in the last 6 months. It's
up 20% in the last 5 years.
>> Explain IGV, please.
>> So, the high-growth software stock
index,
right? Snowflake's
88% in the last 6 months.
>> That's it's an IGV's an ETF of those.
>> IGV is an ETF of of growth software
companies. So, right? So, to to David's
point, there was a panic about software
companies, there was a big trade out.
You know, honestly, they they performed
pretty well, and and as he mentioned, in
the month of July, they were up when a
lot of the semiconductor AI stocks were
down. And some of these companies,
Databricks, Snowflake, ClickHouse, etc.
are doing extraordinarily well. As I
just mentioned, Snowflake's up 90% in
the last 6 months, which puts it in the
same category as the semiconductor AI
stocks. So, to David's point, you can't
throw them all in the same bucket, but I
do think that for these no-code, a lot
of these application software companies,
they're realizing like the you know, the
game is up. Sell the company, get what
you can get. You know, importantly here
in the Airtable story, all the
late-stage investors, right? We passed
on this in the last three funding
rounds, right? Which I think were at 2
billion, 5 billion, 11 billion. But all
those late-stage investors, which were
the most venerable of growth firms, they
all got their money back. And the
early-stage investors ended up making a
lot. So, if this is a failure, this is a
pretty good failure for Silicon Valley.
>> This is one of the points that was made
at that time, which is, "Hey,
this is a strong enough company and team
and revenue base that if we just get our
money with the optionality, hey, maybe
this would be a good investment." You
could say the same thing about some AI
bets. Right, right?
>> of those cases where the liquidation
preference actually mattered. You know,
normally it doesn't matter, but
>> Well, I think they got straight money
here. I My understanding is this wasn't
like they had like a 7%, you know,
interest rate or they didn't have like a
participating preferred where you get
two times your money back and then they
do the trade. Do Does anybody know? Cuz
I looked deeply into this and I couldn't
find it.
>> I think that net of cash they may have
come in a little bit less than the total
cash raised, but it seemed like
everybody got made whole.
>> Yeah. But if they had the I guess Sachs,
there we live through moments in time
where companies had to guarantee a 1X,
right? You know, in the Sachs.
>> 1X liquidation preference is standard.
It just means you get your money back
before other people start to profit,
which is appropriate.
>> But also the interest rates were taken
out, right? Of these deals. Uh I think
during peak ZIRP.
>> The standard terms, you know, what's
known as clean terms. This is a simple
one x liquidation preference. Right. The
preferred just gets their money back
before the common starts to participate
in
a successful sale of the company. That
just makes sense, right?
>> Yeah, but a participating preferred is
the double dip, right?
>> Yeah, and look, we've never done that.
You know, we believe in clean terms. No
one's trying to be punitive towards
founders. It's just It doesn't make
sense for some people in the cap table
to be making money while other people
are losing money.
>> Yeah. It just doesn't make sense, right?
>> up the alignment.
>> that's just a transfer of value from
some people in the cap table to other
people in the cap table. So, the
standard thing you do is you make sure
that the investors get paid back, and
then everybody's participating in the
upside.
>> Okay, fourth story here. China is
training on US data from US providers.
Forbes published an investigation called
These American startups are making
China's AI smarter. And I think this
relates to a lot of your work in the
early part of the administration, Sachs.
They claim US data labeling startups are
selling valuable training data to
Chinese labs, which in turn is helping
them catch up with the US frontier ones.
Two startups, Surge AI and Mercor, are
both valued over $20 They sell training
data sets to people like OpenAI and
Anthropic, federal agencies.
They all sell the same data sets to top
Chinese AI companies, according to this
report, like Tencent, ByteDance,
Alibaba, Moonshot, etc.
Top six AI labs in China, according to
this report, are spending $500 million a
year buying what Forbes calls secret
sauce, PhD written
content, reinforcement learning,
knowledge pipelines, all that kind of
great stuff. I have investments in a
couple of these companies, including
Micro 1.
The founder of Micro 1 didn't
participate in selling to China. He made
that decision, Sachs.
what do you think here about this new
wrinkle in terms of really the secret
sauce behind a lot of these models is
the data. We've run out of
open data on the web, obviously. We
talked last week about the books being
you know, having the spines taken off of
them and scanned in. I mean, people are
looking for data. Merkle or Micro 1, all
these companies are providing it. Should
they be providing the same data and
selling it to Chinese open-source
companies or not?
>> Well, look, I think we got to decide
what our objective is here. Are we
trying to just get in like a full-blown
economic war with China? Are we just
trying to prevent all of our companies
from doing business over there? If
that's our objective, then you can take
that position. Historically, the rules
have been that you want to be careful
about technology transfer of technology
that has a dual use, right? That it has
a military application. My sense of data
is that it's largely a commodity. I
mean, data labeling certainly is. If you
basically tell them that they can't use
data labeling, I guarantee you there's
no shortage of labor in China that they
can use to do the data labeling. In
fact, they probably are. What I'm saying
is there's a lot of ways to get this
data. So, look, if we basically ban
these companies from selling to China,
we should expect reciprocal actions
taken by China to ban companies over
there selling to us, maybe rare earths.
These two countries are not completely
independent of each other. By the way, I
want us to be as independent and
sovereign as possible. I don't want to
have any dependencies, but
>> but we still at this moment in time do
have some dependencies. So, I think you
have to ask the question, is this data
really proprietary? Does it have a dual
use?
>> it's not Does it have a military
application?
>> Yeah, I don't think it has military.
It's definitely not data labeling. This
is like hiring PhDs, hiring super
professionals to you know, create unique
data sets. So, it's science. It's
science.
>> can do that, too, and I guarantee you
they are. I don't think this is going to
give us a decisive advantage in the AI
race. It's going to annoy It's going to
create annoyance. It's going to create
friction. And how bad you want our
relationship with them to be? Do you
want to risk starting another trade war?
Look, I'm not against restrictions when
I think they're going to pack a punch.
For example, I'm really glad that the
first Trump administration limited the
export of EUV lithography machines to
China. You know, that was all the way
back, I think, in 2019.
So, that was a really important
decision. And so, look, I think target
is strategic controls make sense. I
would just make sure that this one
actually meets that bar.
>> Brad, any thoughts here on
this
open-source catch-up, the data being
sold to China and our adversaries? Are
you concerned about these open-source
models and then us providing data to
them?
>> First, you know, I'm in absolute
agreement with David that we want
maximum competition. At as we sit here
today, the US is winning. We talked
about it at the start. Our frontier labs
are winning. Our open source is winning.
And we have fairly limited regulations,
right? She's coming here in September in
a bilateral meeting to meet with the
president. We're advancing relations on
a variety of fronts. So, I think
everything looks good, and you want to
continue down that path. With that said,
I will tell you that this will irritate
people in Washington who feel that this,
along with distillation and other
things, um could be the export of chips,
all of which, at a certain level, make
sense, cause people to wonder whether or
not we're making it too easy on the
Chinese labs to catch up with American
labs,
uh you know, in the race to frontier
intelligence. So, it you know, it's the
type of story, Jason, that I think will
continue to muddy the waters, that will
continue uh to be monitored. The reason
I I think it will cause us to change our
stance with respect to China is because
we're winning.
But if the president asks his advisors,
you know, one of these days, 6 months
down the line, are we winning against
China? And all of a sudden he gets a
response, no, we're no longer winning,
they've caught up, they've passed us,
etc., then these things will get a lot
more scrutiny than they're getting
today. I think the only reason they pass
muster today is because we're still
leading the race.
>> I got to say, using Kimmy and Gwen and,
you know, GLM 52 for the last 60 days,
my lord, these things are good and I
don't think it's very patriotic to be
giving them an advantage. I wouldn't do
it. I'm glad the company
>> Sorry, what's the advantage? What's the
data set that you you're worried about
that's so proprietary?
>> Any of these data sets are
created by experts here in America who
are given like the queries that have
errors in them. So when you give
you know, a thumbs down to a query
that's highly technical, it could be
code, it could be biology and science.
These are, you know, PhDs going in there
and putting in the latest and greatest
content and then verifying it, double
verifying it, and that's why we're
getting better and better results out of
the LLMs. So essentially, you're just
helping them catch up. And this could be
a big advantage for America if we
weren't sending it there. I think a big
reason these models are getting better
is because data is being leaked to them.
>> But what makes you think that China
can't do this? They have tons of PhDs
over there.
>> They would have to hire No, no. If they
were to do it at this scale, they would
need to hire the best and brightest uh
scientists and experts in the West. So
basically, all the knowledge of the West
is being um
you know, put into packages for our LLMs
to get better. They're sending those
same packages and reselling them to
Chinese companies, which means they
catch up just as quick. I think it's a
big part of why they're catching up. It
in line with distillation, you know,
they're it's it's really very similar
process.
>> Look, if there's something truly
proprietary here, I don't want us to
sell our secret sauce to China. So, you
know, I'd have to look into that and see
like is there some real secret sauce
here? But this idea that it would
seriously disadvantage China, you know,
they're graduating more math and science
graduates every year than the rest of
the world combined. I mean,
they don't have a shortage of smart
people, especially in China.
>> and kicking them out of the country.
That's the other problem. We got to get
that fixed.
>> Well, it's like this a lot of different
issues here. I don't know how many you
want to conflate, but I this idea that
they can't but
this idea that they can't recreate those
data sets. I mean, look, if there's
something truly proprietary here, if it
has a dual use, if it's military
related, but I don't know that that's
what this is.
>> Well, they're all proprietary in my
design, but I don't know about the dual
use cuz I don't have the data sets here.
All right, folks, that's another amazing
episode of your All-In podcast. Thank
you so much, Brad, for joining us.
Chamath, good luck on your world tour.
Hope you're enjoying a little rest and
good luck trying to buy a white
turtleneck this season. They're sold out
everywhere. So, go to the allin.com
store, allin.com/store.
We have 1,000 signature Chamath
autographed white sweaters coming. You
can sign up in advance for those. All
proceeds go to charity. By charity,
I mean Chamath's yacht fund. All right,
we'll see you next week, everybody.
Bye-bye.
>> [music]
>> Let your winners ride.
>> Rain Man, David Sacks.
>> And I said, we [music] open sourced it
to the fans and they've just gone crazy
with it.
>> Love you, Sacks.
>> Ice Queen of Quinoa.
>> [music]
>> Besties are ballers.
>> Best co-parent ever.
>> That is my dog taking a dump in your
[music] driveway, Sacks.
>> Oh, man.
>> My guy Chamath will meet me at the
restaurant.
>> We should all [music] just get a room
and just have a one big huge orgy
because they're all just useless. It's
like this like sexual tension that they
just need to release somehow.
>> Wet your big feet.
>> Wet your pure feet.
>> [laughter]
>> What?
>> We need to get merch.
>> I'm going all in.
>> [music]
>> I'm going [music] all in.